<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Alexander Wong</title>
    <link>https://alexander-wong.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Alexander Wong</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© 2017 Alexander Wong</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://alexander-wong.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Self</title>
      <link>https://alexander-wong.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexander-wong.com/about/</guid>
      <description>About My name is Alexander Wong. I occasionally write software. I am the CEO of Udia Software Incorporated.
When I&amp;rsquo;m not working on Udia, I spend my time running or hiking. In the winter, I ski. I enjoy playing my guitar and listening to folk music. Some of my long term goals include living out of a van to travel around the continent and building an earthship sustainable home.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning, Week 2</title>
      <link>https://alexander-wong.com/post/coursera-machine-learning-week2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2017 14:05:35 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexander-wong.com/post/coursera-machine-learning-week2/</guid>
      <description>Taking the Coursera Machine Learning course. Will post condensed notes every week as part of the review process. All material originates from the free Coursera course, taught by Andrew Ng.
Assumes you have knowledge of Week 1.
Table of Contents  Linear Regression with Multiple Variables  Multivariate Linear Regression  Multiple Features Gradient Descent for Multiple Variables Gradient Descent in Practice - Feature Scaling &amp;amp; Mean Normalization Gradient Descent in Practice - Learning Rate Features and Polynomial Regression  Computing Parameters Analytically  Normal Equation Normal Equation Noninvertibility   Optional Octave/MatLab Tutorial  Octave Tutorial  Basic Operations Moving Data Around Computing on Data Plotting Data Functions &amp;amp; Control Statements: for, while, if/elseif/else Vectorization      Lecture notes:  Lecture4 Lecture5   Linear Regression with Multiple Variables Multivariate Linear Regression Multiple Features Linear regression with multiple variables is known as Multivariate Linear Regression.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning, Week 1</title>
      <link>https://alexander-wong.com/post/coursera-machine-learning-week1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2017 10:25:51 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexander-wong.com/post/coursera-machine-learning-week1/</guid>
      <description>Taking the Coursera Machine Learning course. Will post condensed notes every week as part of the review process. All material originates from the free Coursera course, taught by Andrew Ng.
Table of Contents  Introduction  Machine Learning  What is Machine Learning Supervised Learning Unsupervised Learning  Linear Regression with One Variable  Model Representation Cost Function &amp;amp; Intuitions Gradient Descent Gradient Descent for Linear Regression   Optional Linear Algebra  Linear Algebra Review  Matrices and Vectors Matrix Addition and Scalar Operations Matrix-Vector Multiplication Matrix-Matrix Multiplication Matrix Multiplication Properties Inverse and Transpose      Lecture notes:  Lecture1 Lecture2 Lecture3   Introduction Machine Learning What is Machine Learning  Arthur Samuel (1959): The field of study that gives computers the ability to learn without explicitly programmed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello World</title>
      <link>https://alexander-wong.com/post/hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2017 14:25:51 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexander-wong.com/post/hello-world/</guid>
      <description>Although as individuals we are always in transition, I believe it is necesary to have static markers representing our current state in reference to the universe. We are mortal, we were born into this world, and inevitably we will eventually die. Consider this post to mark the beginning of a quarter life transition. I figure that the best way to measure and document this is to have an open, publicly available record of my goals and my journey in pursuing meaning in life.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>